This is the Cerise 4U by FTSLED
and it's absolutely
my favorite transmitter right now.
In fact it's
such a perfect match with Blackout
that I'm now selling these on my website.
The Cerise is what everyone hoped the
Ratpack AKS would evolve to, as it requires
just one cable that both powers
it and gives it data over network.
It literally requires no setup
to get started using it with Blackout, yet
has some of the most powerful features
packed into it with its evolving web GUI.
Let's take a look.
There are three flavors of the Cerise.
The 1U, 2U, and 4U which correspond
to how many wireless universes
they can transmit.
However, the 2U and 4U both
have the ability to send an additional
four universes
via a wired RJ45 cable to a breakout box.
So if you're running a big rig
that gives you up to eight universes total
four over the air and four over wire,
all from one unit.
If that's not enough, both the 2U and 4U
can also take POE
or Power Over Ethernet.
so go ahead and skip
the separate power cable for those of us
running POE switches in our rigs.
But I think what's most catchy
about these transmitters is that they are
incredibly slim and light.
Just look at this.
The build quality is top notch.
It's a robust
all metal design with mounting
holes,
making it ridiculously versatile to rig.
Strap this onto the back of your iPad,
or screw it onto a cage,
and you are walking around
with a powerhouse
console with the ability to transmit up
to four universes wherever you go.
It makes lighting control a dream.
Now the coolest part.
All models can actually be powered
and fed data with just one cable.
So here we go. I'm running Blackout.
I plug this baby in,
I press link to link my fixtures and bam!
Up and running.
It doesn't get easier than that.
Now, of course it does
suck juice from the iPad, but now you only
have to monitor battery in one place.
And with the included Anker USB-C hub,
you can power the iPad either
with an external battery
or plug it into the wall
when you set it down
without breaking connection to the Cerise.
Remember the AKS?
If you were to shut it down
and then restart it,
it actually zeroed out all of the data,
and it would cause
your entire set to turn off
if you were within range of your light,
which was very problematic.
If you ever had this happen to you.
The Cerise doesn't do that.
I can unplug it, then plug it back in
and I'm back where I started.
Nothing to worry about.
Plus, it boots in roughly seven seconds,
which is five seconds
faster than the Skycast-C.
It doesn't seem like much,
but it can make a big difference
in those time critical situations.
If you've ever had to juggle
an iPad power situation,
come on, we've all been there.
If we dive into the web GUI,
the easiest way to get there from an iPad
is just go to your network settings
and look at the name of the device,
which shows you its IP.
It will also give the device
you are connected to an IP
one digit higher than what
the node is currently set at.
So here I'll just copy
and paste this in a web browser
and now change the number to one less.
And now you can see the web GUI.
It's even easier if you plug this
into a computer with a USB-C cable,
because you get this sleek pop up
that takes you right there.
Besides the traditional device and network
settings, you have full customization
of each universe output.
Here, I can change the universe,
including selecting a merge mode.
If using more than one source,
I can link or unlink fixtures per antenna
and even set the linking key per antenna.
Now remember Lumen Radio has locked down
CRMX squared,
so no one can transmit multiple universes
over a single antenna.
But everyone can still use
the linking key.
Here you are able to set a different
linking key per antenna.
And if you're not familiar with what
this linking key is, it's the nice ability
to link fixtures to an antenna
by simply inputting this key
into the light fixture itself,
which can be super handy
when you are batch configuring
a bunch of lights like Asteras.
No more having to carry the transmitter
with you in order to link.
You can set this in the fixture
if you're on the reading crew
and then when your main unit
comes with their transmitter with the same
linking key, you're good to go
because the lights
will automatically search
for that transmitter
with that linking key and connect up.
So each antenna has to have its own
linking key in order for this
to work on third party products
like the Cerise.
And when you pair to this,
you just make sure
that you are in universe
A connecting via regular CRMX.
Only the Stardust can support a single
linking key across all antennas
with CRMX squared, so that's an incredibly
convenient feature on the Cerise.
The little megaphone icon
is where you can set the transmit power,
and the Bluetooth icon
allows you to enable or disable Bluetooth,
allowing you to connect up
to each CRMX chip with LumenRadio CRMX
toolbox app in case you need to update it.
If you look at the top,
you can go to the console tab.
If you need to just flash out a few things
manually.
The spectrum tab to see if you are getting
any wireless interference.
And the help tab for quick access to help.
Although it's not officially released yet.
RDM support is on the way,
and it brings some exciting capabilities
with the upcoming RDM tab.
You'll be able to view fixture data
like temperature, battery life, and other
key stats directly within the web GUI.
Even more useful, RDM
lets you remotely change the DMX address
or mode of a fixture.
No need to walk over or climb a ladder.
It's another step towards
faster workflows, smarter control,
and a more efficient lighting experience.
So stay tuned for that release.
The Cerise 4U isn't just
my favorite transmitter right now.
It's what the AKS should have become.
It's rugged, reliable, and ridiculously
easy to use in a very compact size.
You can get up to eight universes
from a single unit, seamless
Blackout integration with zero setup
and a slick web GUI that's actually useful.
I'm now selling the Cerise lineup
directly on Blackout’s website
because I believe in this product
that much.
The creator, Charlie, genuinely cares
about delivering something of real value
to working professionals.
If you're serious about wireless control
and want a rock solid
upgrade to your setup, this is it.
Hey, thanks for watching.
Tell me what you think about the Cerise
in the comments below,
and I'll catch you in the next video.